# Yasha Kuruvilla

# **Business Analyst**

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Software Engineering TA | BrainStation**

AUG 2022 - NOV 2022, LONDON, UK

- Conducted code review for ~20 students on multiple React projects
- Graded assignments and provided personalised feedback on progress
- Provided 1-on-1 mentorship for students

### Business Analyst | Zego

JUN 2021 - APR 2022, LONDON, UK

- Spearheaded the rebuild of Zego's B2B insurance web application enabling faster development of new features and improving scalability.
- Liaised with internal stakeholders to ensure new features were prioritised correctly.
- Conducted sprint reviews to keep stakeholders abreast of new releases.

## Associate Analyst / Analyst (Insurance) | GlobalData

DEC 2018 - JUN 2021, LONDON, UK

- Built interactive Tableau dashboards allowing clients to gain strategic insights into their markets.
- Designed and deployed a B2B survey of over 2,000 UK SMEs which formed the foundation of over 10 reports.
- Implemented new models to improve the accuracy of survey results by over 50%.
- Delivered live online webinars to over 50 clients to highlight key insurance developments during COVID-19.

#### Finance Associate | Management Systems International

JUN 2018 - SEP 2018, ARLINGTON, VA, USA

- Collaborated with a team of over 50 project managers with the budgeting of multimillion-dollar United States Agency for International Development (USAID) projects.
- Produced financial reports to optimise project profitability by monitoring costs and projecting cash flow.

#### **PROJECTS**

Watchdle - A Wordle styled game based on Overwatch 2

 Full stack app built with NextJS utilising Mongodb, and deployed with Vercel

**Asteroids** -An arcade style game based on Atari's Asteroids

Built using Vanilla JS

yasha.kuruvilla@gmail.com +44 7988 998504 https://www.linkedin.com/in/yas ha-kuruvilla/ https://github.com/ykuruvilla

#### **PROFILE**

Insurance analyst with experience identifying problems and trends through data. I am shifting into the software engineering field to build the solutions to those problems. My previous experience within a product team will ensure that I always fall in love with the problem, not the solution.

#### **SKILLS**

Amplitude, APIs, CSS, DOM APIs, Enzyme, Express.js, Git, GitHub, Heroku, HTML, JavaScript, Jest, Jira, Kanban, MongoDB, Mongoose, MySQL, NextJS, React.js Scrum, Socket.IO, Tableau Tailwind, Typescript, User Authentication, Vercel, WebPack

#### **Education**

BrainStation Diploma,
Web Development

MAY 2022 - AUG 2022 , LONDON, UK

The George Washington
University,
BSc Economics,
Minor Mathematics

JAN 2014-2017, WASHINGTON, DC Magna Cum Laude